-它还活着吗  -妈妈  它没事吧
- Is it alive? - Mommy, is it okay?
妈妈  救救它
Mommy, fix it. Make it better.
姑娘们  妈妈马上就回来  好吗
Girls, girls, Mommy's gonna be right back, okay?
它的翅膀怎么了
Why don't its wings work?
戈登  它还有气吗
Gordon, is it breathing?
快没了
Barely.
小心沾上螨虫
Yeah, watch out for mites.
我们能做点什么吗
Well, is there something we can do?
-喂点水  或者...  -那都无济于事了
- Give it some water, or... - I think we're beyond that.
我该带它去看兽医
I should take it to the vet.
亲爱的  孩子们要去上学
Honey, the girls have to get to school.
你的车还在修理店
And with your car in the shop...
是  你说得对
Yeah, yeah, you're right.
要搭车吗  邻居
Hey, you need a ride, neighbor?
那真是太好了
Oh, that would be so great.
-多谢了  布莱恩  -没关系
- Yeah, thanks, Brian. - Hey, no problemo.
可怜的小东西
Poor little sucker.
放手听凭天意  对吧
Let go, let God, right?
伙计
Hey, man.
今天别紧张
Don't sweat today.
你能行的
You can do this.
声级表
不是你的错
Look, it's not your fault.
不是任何人的错
It's no one's fault.
这就像冬天下了场早雪
It's like when you get an early snow
把柑橘林冻坏了
and it freezes your orange grove.
果农不得已只能另寻办法供应果汁了
And then the farmer has to find another way to deliver the juice.
哪怕每片雪花都和你一样
Even if every snowflake is totally unique
独特
like you.
-戈登  你搞什么  -你安排在11点45
- Gordon, what the hell? - You're my 11:45.
你让我们像一群白痴似的在外面乱转
You got us milling around out there like a bunch of Frenchmen.
兰迪  我正和人谈事呢
Randy, I'm with someone.
我可以排队等着坐摩天轮
I'll wait in line for a Ferris wheel.
排队等着买啤酒
I'll wait in line for a beer.
但绝不会坐等到11点45
But damned if I'll wait around till 11:45
让你和乔·麦克米伦开除我
to get fired by flipping you or flipping Joe MacMillan.
你要开除我吗
Wait, you're firing me?
-我这是要被开除了吗  -冷静点
- I'm being fired? - Just calm down.
我的推荐信
My reference letter.
别担心  我都写好了
And don't worry, I wrote it myself.
签名
Sign it.
天啊  我得给帕蒂打电话
Oh, my God, I gotta call Patty.
我要说
And can I just say
代表这个曾经辉煌的公司
on behalf of a once-great company,
我很期待有天开车经过这里
I look forward to driving past here
看到草坪上钉着"出租"的牌子
when the "For Lease" signs get nailed to the lawn
而你的个人电脑幻想则土崩瓦解
and your little PC vision quest crashes and burns.
28磅
28 pounds.
这不是便携  顶多是可携
That's not portable, that's luggable.
分发的资料上的销售额
And those are the combined sales figures
是科乐  微泰和雅达利三家的总和
for Coleco, Vectrex, and Atari.
-那是电子游戏  -是微机
- Video games. - Microcomputers.
这证明美国人渴望拥有这些电器
Proof that America wants these machines in their homes.
而个人电脑行业作何回应呢
And how did the PC business respond?
他们塞给消费者的是录音机  缝纫机和化油器
With a cassette deck, a sewing machine, and a carburetor.
我们才不要造这些大块头
We're not making a carburetor.
我们要造的  是这个
We're making this.
年底前
By the end of this year,
卡迪夫电子将向市场郑重推出
Cardiff Electric will release to the market
一款真正的便携式电脑  配有双磁盘驱动器
a truly portable computer with two disk drives,
一体式屏幕  和键盘
integrated screen, and keyboard,
其总重  不超过15磅
weighing no more than 15 pounds.
稍微懂点微处理的人都知道
Anyone that knows anything about microprocessing...
你是不是算错数了  戈登
You've got that number wrong, right, Gordon?
这配置至少得花个一百万
It's gonna take a million dollars
造出来也是这桌子的四倍
and four times the size of this desk...
没错  你们说的都对
Yes, that's correct.
这的确很有野心
It's ambitious.
你知道谁最懂屏幕这块吗
You know who was good with screens?
-兰迪  -没错
- Randy. - Sure was.
话说他哪去了  对了  他被你炒了
Say, where is Randy? Oh, that's right, you fired him.
赶紧去停车场追吧  没准还能截住他
Run out to the parking lot. Maybe you can flag him down.
-戈登  出来一下  -几位  冷静一下
- Gordon, outside. - Guys, relax.
-我冷静个头  -醒醒吧  布莱恩
- No, I'm not relaxing. - Wake up, Brian.
过去好歹我们造的东西还卖得出去
We used to build products that people would buy.
现在净说疯话了
We're not even in reality anymore.
-听着  -拉里  现在的局面就是...
- Listen-- - Larry, we're dealing with--
你就挑了这几块料
These are the guys you chose?
今早我开了46个人之后  就剩这些了
After I let go of 46 people this morning,
我本来就不该负责开人
something I'm in no way qualified to do.
我更担心他们的态度
I'm worried about their attitude.
他们的态度基于物理定律
Their attitude is based on the laws of physics,
换做我是你  就认真学学物理
which, if I were you, I'd bone up on.
这些工程师是我们仅剩的
You're looking at our only engineers
有微处理器相关经验的人了
with any microprocessor experience at all.
就剩他们了  所以没错  就这几块料
They're what's left, so, yeah, these are my guys.
你最起码等我们走了再来扫荡吧
You could at least wait until we've left the building.
谢谢你
Oh, thank you!
不够好
散热器要装在哪里
Where do we put the heat sink?
如果限频是4兆赫的话  也许用不着散热器
Well, we run it at four megahertz, maybe we don't need one.
不行  那样太慢
No, it's too slow.
克雷格·詹姆斯比迪克森动作慢
Craig James was slow compared to Dickerson.
两人皆为橄榄球员
但他也够快的了
Still plenty fast enough.
肯定有什么办法能既提速又不升温
There's gotta be a way to add speed without adding heat.
要不在里面装个煎锅  过热了还能煎肉
Or you can build in a griddle and fry steaks on it.
你打算给这房间起个什么名字
What do you want to call this place?
"臭鼬工厂"已经被人抢了
I guess "Skunk Works" is taken.
美国航空航天公司高级开发项目的官方认可绰号
-"芯片组圣堂"  -"逻辑之巢"
- "The Chamber of Chipsets." - "Logic Lair."
说不定我们最后会在这儿自相残杀
We're probably gonna end up killing each other in here
甚至自杀
and ourselves.
那就叫"杀戮室"吧
Well, let's call it "The Kill Room."
挺好
Not bad.
所以他用抵押的钱还
So he uses the collateral to repay the money
他为买下那东西借的债
he borrowed to purchase the target.
真是聪明啊
Pretty brilliant, right?
-这是谁  -亚伦·利特菲尔德
- Who the hell's that? - Aaron Littlefield,
艾格-利特菲尔德风险投资
Eiger & Littlefield Venture Capital.
风险投资
"Venture Capital"?
以前我们就管那叫钱呢
Hell, I remember when it was still called "money."
就给他五分钟  他从纽约飞来的呢
Give him five minutes. He just flew in from New York.
-抱歉  我吃过午饭了  -我们也是
- Sorry, I already had lunch. - So did we.
《日报》上常报道硅草原
They keep reading about the Silicon Prairie in the "Journal."
他们有资金  而且愿意进入这个市场
They have cash to spend and they want exposure to this market.
我们的个人电脑是个不错的切入点
Our PC could be a nice entry point.
你知道我还得请示内森吧
You know I gotta clear all this with Nathan.
我跟他谈过了
I already have.
亚伦
Aaron.
我是约翰·博斯沃思  很高兴见到你
Hey, John Bosworth here. Nice to meet ya.
-飞行顺利吗  -有些颠簸  不过值得
- How was the flight? - Oh, a little bumpy, but worth it.
那太好了  我也希望值得
Well, good. I sure as shit hope so.
我已经找到了印刷电路板的故障
I've identified the bugs in the PCBs.
恐怕得召回一万台左右
We're gonna have to recall about 10,000 units.
但更重要的是键盘回弹问题
But the bigger problem is with the keyboard bouncing.
我们最好能重新设计这个...
If we could just redesign the trim, then--
但那不属于我们的责任  对吧
But that's not our purview, right?
我什么时候能告诉马克
How soon can I tell Mark?
周一  最迟周二
Monday, Tuesday at the latest.
-你父母还好吗  -很好  谢谢
- Your folks are well? - Oh, great. Thank you.
我就见过这一对父母
Only parents I ever knew who
去为木琴演奏者喝彩
came to the game to cheer on the xylophonist.
玛汀还好吗
And how's Martine?
她以为在德州仪器干就不用离开德州呢
Well, she thought that Texas Instruments meant staying in Texas.
这是我们5年来的第三站了
This is our third stop in five years, so...
我觉得她想要安定下来  但...
I think she wants to settle down, but--
但往上爬可不能停下
But that's not the way you climb the ladder.
真不敢相信我们的谈话
I can't believe we're talking like this--
往上爬  季度目标什么的
climbing ladders, quarterly targets.
我们离开高中真是好久了
We are a long way from high school.
感谢上帝  我那时的发型和乐队队服
Oh, well, thank God. My hair and that band uniform.
我们都知道你不合适做乐队
Hey, we all knew that you weren't cut out for band.
你只是想打发时间
You were just marking time,
等待更好的未来
waiting for something better to come along.
唐娜
Donna...
不是想为难你
not to be a pain,
但是我明天要和马克见面
but I'm meeting with Mark tomorrow
你的报告会很有用
and that report would be helpful.
好的
Oh, okay.
我会交给你的
You'll have it.
麦克米伦先生办公室
Mr. MacMillan's office.
卡梅伦吗
Cameron?
我们有理想的商业环境  无可限量的发展前景
We have got an ideal business climate. Unlimited growth curve.
而且刚被IBM打得屁滚尿流
And you just got your ass handed to you by IBM.
他们试过了  但没成功
They took their shot. They missed.
但系统程序包挣的钱快花光了  对吧
But the cash from your system packages is running out, correct?
伙计们  我迟早也会知道
Guys, I'm gonna find out anyway.
-怎么说  -我们跟你们合伙
- How's that? - Well, we partner with you,
就得详细审查你们的账面
we audit your books top to bottom,
任命高管到你们公司
install upper management on-site,
应该是罗杰
probably Roger.
-你向他报告  -罗杰
- You'd report to him. - Roger?
这个想法还在讨论中
It's just an option we're discussing.
-午饭时谈的吗  -没错
- At lunch? - That's right.
或许与其派一个人来
You know, maybe instead of sending someone out,
不如你每周打个电话
you do a weekly call.
伙计们  展示日期都还没谈呢
Guys, I haven't even heard a rollout date yet, okay?
你们的营销策略是什么
What's your marketing strategy?
打算怎么重新建立客户群体
How do you plan on rebuilding your client base here?
我们有全新的客户群了
We got a whole new client base.
是的  乔打算让这款机器面向大众
Yeah, Joe here wants to take this machine to the people.
不再只卖给企业
Yeah, no more biz-to-biz.
我们要挨家挨户  走街串巷
We're pushing doorbells and pounding pavement.
还会有高端的媒体宣传
Along with a sophisticated media campaign.
高端什么啊  得了吧  乔
Oh, sophisticated, my ass. Come on, Joe.
我们受够了这些华而不实的发布和公司策略
We're tired of these doodad launches and corporate suites.
我想接地气
No, I wanna breathe me some air.
小店啦  乡村集市啦
You know, mom-and-pop stores, county fairs.
我们目前是没有业绩也没有资产负债表
Now, we may not have the track record or the balance sheet,
但我发誓  我们有决心
but, by God, we got heart.
有诚挚的德州精神
The can-do Texas spirit, y'all.
我家电话在背面
My home number's on the back.
随时欢迎致电
I want you to call the ranch anytime.
我会的
Sure will.
我给你看些策划吧
Let me show you some sketches.
很高兴再次见到你  乔
It's so good seeing you again, Joe.
我们再联系
I'll be in touch.
让他们走吧  好吗
What do you think? Let 'em go?
午夜之前就走吗
What, before midnight?
靠最后冲刺是赢不了的
You can't win a race at the quarter pole.
真的  对他们好一点
Seriously, buy yourself some goodwill with these guys.
好吧  谢谢大家
All right, thanks, everyone.
回家吧
Have a good night.
尤其我们还想
Especially if we try
把一块更大的主板塞进一个更小的箱子里
and cram a bigger motherboard into a smaller case.
不管怎样  换晶振  超频CPU
Either way, we swap out the crystal and we overclock the CPU.
那样内部温度会升高  就需要更大的散热器
Which heats up the innards, which means a bigger heat sink.
别忘了  我们才抛弃了散热器
And may I remind you, we just ditched the heat sink.
怎么样了
Hey, how's it going?
-不准接触  忘了吗  -我知道
- No contact, remember? - I know, I know.
我不是想打听什么
Look, I don't mean to pry.
我知道才过了一周  你压力也很大
I know it's only been a week and you're under a lot of pressure,
但要是你能给我们透露点大致...
but if you could just give us some sort of idea as to--
我去订披萨
I'll order a pizza.
她拿走了我的苏打水
She took my soda.
要想忘了生活多不顺心  泡泡浴是最佳办法
Nothing like a bubble bath to make you forget life's little traumas.
-我觉得管用  -我们还给他们买了点东西
- Works for me. - Oh, we also got them a little something.
不用这么客气的
Oh, you shouldn't have.
安息吧  鲍瑟
"鲍瑟"吗
"Bowser"?
可不像鸟的名字
It's not exactly a bird's name.
可怜的小家伙现在应该已经死了
Poor thing's dead by now.
随便怎么叫他都行了
I expect you can call it whatever you like.
那是肖邦的《葬礼进行曲》吗
Is that Chopin's "Funeral March"?
日本人勤奋得过头  看这个
The Japanese never sleep. Look here.
这是我们杂志这个月的封底
It's our back pager this month.
你父亲觉得我们能卖个五十万
Your father thinks we'll move half a million.
真像他  我"毫不怀疑"
"No-doubt" dad.
这可是做分类广告  亲爱的
It's a catalogue business, darling.
"怀疑总是存在"
"There's always doubt."
别告诉戈登是我们送的
Now, don't go telling Gordon it's from us.
我知道他不喜欢这样
I know he doesn't approve.
他加班吗
He working late?
他有个新项目
He's got a new project.
一定让他时不时洗洗盘子啊
Well, make sure he does the dishes sometime.
我爱我女婿
I love my son-in-law,
但我不希望你忙活到人老珠黄
but I don't wanna see you worn down to a nub.
怎么  你觉得我人老珠黄吗
Why, do I seem nubbish to you?
你还是那么容光焕发
You are radiant, as always.
在德州仪器干得怎么样
How's life at TI?
亨特搬回来后  我们还没在俱乐部里见过他
You know, we haven't even seen Hunt at the club since he moved back.
埋头苦干着呢
Well, nose to the grindstone.
可能独立日那天
Well, maybe Fourth of July,
他会来炫耀下他的外国老婆
he'll show off that foreign wife of his.
-妈  她是加拿大人  -她现在客居我们国家
- Mom, she's Canadian. - She is a guest of this country.
完全可以像我们一样挥挥旗子  点点火
She can wave a flag and light something on fire like the rest of us.
我觉得他们不会在达拉斯久留
Well, I don't think they'll be in Dallas long.
如果高层喜欢他  可能会外派
If management likes him, they'll probably ship him overseas.
老亨特在维也纳  或是意大利罗马
Old Hunt in Vienna or Rome, Italy.
想象得到吗
Can you imagine?
-这里不错啊  -人得有个逃避的地方
- This is very nice. - A man needs to seek shelter.
相信在这点上我们是一样的
I believe we have that in common.
我们不只需要投资  还得找明白人投资
We don't just need money. We need smart money.
需要名声  需要人帮我们出名
A name. Someone who puts us on the map.
是的  我知道
Yeah, I know.
你没有做错
You weren't wrong to do what you did,
但约翰也没做错
but then, neither was John.
点了两杯威士忌  我替你挑了个
A little scotch here, and... I guessed.
我们放你进来  乔  也给了你机会
We let you in the door, Joe, we gave you the rope.
但只有一个人能做主
But only one boss-dick can swing it.
你是目标远大的那个
Now, you're the vision guy
我已经退休了  不想重出江湖
and I'm retired and I want to stay retired.
所以约翰得给我寄支票
The way that works is that John here sends me my checks,
让我锦衣玉食  开开心心
keeps me fat and happy.
所以由约翰来做这个项目的财政决策
So John makes the financial decisions on this project,
所有财政决策
all of them.
同意
Agreed.
很好
Good.
别再在背后搞什么鬼了
No more backstage bullshit.
我会安排你跟露易丝·卢瑟福会面
I'm gonna set you up with Louise Lutherford.
-她是我们的老朋友  -挺不好对付的
- An old friend of ours. - Mm-hmm, she is a handful...
但她有足够的资金帮我们度过这关
but she's got more than enough capital to see us through.
而且她是当地人  不是外来的
And she's local, so no "Rogers."
这是挺好
Yeah, that's all well and good,
但她是否了解...
but does she have a background in--
晚上好  赛斯
Good evening, Seth.
卡迪夫先生  还要点餐吗
Mr. Cardiff. Are we dining tonight?
你知道的  我要小份菲力牛排
Oh, you know it. I'll have the petit fillet.
全熟  配豌豆和土豆泥
Burn it, and peas and mash.
牛腰肉  一分熟
Porterhouse, rare. Rare.
我要和他一样的
I'll have the same.
我们可以把键盘嵌在底盖上
I mean, we could recess the keyboard in the bottom cover
然后让线缆穿过铰链
and run the connector cable through the hinges.
好啊  从来没人这么做过
Okay. No one's ever done that before.
那就不能这么做了吗
Well, does that mean it can't be done?
不是  只是成本太高
No, just expensive.
不然要怎么留出安装屏幕的地方啊
Well, how else are we gonna make room for the screen?
戈登  不是我要扫你的兴
Gordon, I'm not trying to yuck your yum here.
没人比我更希望这能成功了
No one wants this to work more than me.
这个概念惊为天人  但要执行起来
It's a hell of a concept, but to execute it...
-很不容易  -我知道  我知道
- ...that's tough sleddin'. - I know, I know.
明天一大早  坐下来跟乔好好谈谈
First thing tomorrow, we sit down with Joe,
让他认清现实  告诉他这是不可能的
bring him back to Earth, tell him it can't be done.
如果需要  我可以陪着你
I'll fly wingman if you want.
不不  我来告诉他
No, no, I'll tell him.
怎么了
What?
你之前来过电话
You called earlier.
不  我没有
No, I don't--
好吧  好吧  我打错了
yes, fine, yes, I did by mistake.
你想怎么样
What? What do you want?
我就是问问情况
Just checking in.
我这儿一切正常
Okay, I'm all checked.
-我就是想知道  -怎么花这么久
- I just wanted to know... - What's taking so long?
你是个很有天赋的程序员
You're a talented coder,
可现在你是我们的瓶颈
but right now you're a bottleneck.
你考虑过去做励志演讲吗
Have you considered motivational speaking?
你蛮有天赋的  伙计
'Cause you've got a gift, man.
说真的  我报名参加  把磁带寄给我吧
Seriously, sign me up. Send me the tapes.
需要我下去找你吗
Do I need to come down there?
不
No.
-那我就...  -再见
- Then I guess I'll-- - See ya.
抱歉我没见着你妈
Sorry I missed your mother.
你偷着乐呢吧
No, you're not.
至少鸟已经死了
At least the bird's gone.
孩子们都很不开心  几乎没吃东西
The girls were so upset, they barely ate.
是吗
Yeah?
也许不是吃鸡肉的最佳时机
Maybe not the best night for chicken.
你觉得还要花多久
So, how much longer, do you think?
几个小时吧
Couple hours.
你这设计挺有意思的
That's an interesting layout.
如果都能放下的话
If I can make it all fit.
你能帮我...
Can you take a--
不行  戈登  我得先做完这个
No, Gordon, I have to finish this.
你说得对  我很抱歉
You're right, you're right. I'm sorry.
-其实有个地方可以改一下  -哪里
- Well, you know what you could do? - What?
你可以改变中断控制器的位置
You could move the interrupt controller
然后可以把奇偶校验内存芯片挪到下面
and then maybe scootch those parity RAM chips down.
-你介不介意我...  -不不  你来
- Do you mind if I-- - No, no, no.
-归你了  -这里  还有这里
- All yours. - Here and here.
如果你旋转这些DMA控制器  腾出空间
Then if you rotate these DMA controllers to make room,
直接内存访问控制器  用于提升外设通讯效率
就可以
you can...
等等  等等  什么
Wait, wait, wait, what?
做成复式的
Piggyback it.
-流水的软件  -铁打的硬件
- Software comes and goes... - Hardware is forever.
好吧
Okay.
好吧  这有点意思
Okay, okay, that's interesting.
那是劳埃德的鞋子吗
Those Lloyd's shoes?
劳埃德是什么人
Who the hell's Lloyd?
拜托
Come on.
劳埃德是个很厉害的保龄球手
Lloyd... one hell of a bowler.
虔诚的路德教信徒  有三个孩子
Good Lutheran, three kids.
今早我不得不把他开除了
I had to fire him this morning.
你觉得这样好吗
You think it's a good idea
穿着被开除的人的鞋子走来走去
walking around in a dead man's shoes?
你要去哪  小丫头
Where are you headed, young lady?
这是你第一份工作吧  我没猜错吧
This is your first job, huh? Am I right?
这就下班之后在办公室里到处乱翻了
You're already rooting around the offices after hours?
我听说公司最近资金紧张
I heard money's tight around here.
所以想关灯省点电
I thought I'd switch off your light.
"Go To"和"Go Sub"有什么区别
What is the difference between "Go To" and "Go Sub"?
均为汇编语言指令
"Go To"执行它指向的语句
"Go To" executes the next line.
而"Go Sub"需要在结尾加上返回命令
"Go Sub," You need, like, a return command at the end.
我完全看不懂
That makes no sense to me.
一开始是有点难
Yeah, it's hard at the beginning.
如果不是因为你朋友乔
If it weren't for your friend Joe...
我现在已经回家了
I'd be home right now.
他很特别  是吧
He's different, huh?
乔
Joe?
好好保管这双鞋
You take care of those shoes.
卡梅伦
And, Cameron?
你想工作到多晚都可以
You can work here as late as you'd like.
但不能住在这里
You cannot live here.
我们有办法了
I think we can make this work.
如果我们将主板分成两部分
If we actually split the motherboard
然后叠在一起
and then layer
一半放在另一半上面
one half on top of the other,
将跳线垂直放置
run the jumpers vertically.
这样每一部分上面的芯片数可以翻倍
So you're doubling the amount of chips on each half.
-没错  -有意思
- Yeah. - Interesting.
你怎么想到的
Where'd you get that idea?
在厨房里想到的
In my kitchen.
这是能给我们省下几厘米的空间
It'd buy us a couple centimeters, for sure.
-干得好  -如果我们能固定住支持点的话
- Nice work. - If we can stabilize the vertices.
就不能让我们乐呵会儿吗  斯坦
Hey, why don't you let it ride for a cycle, Stan?
唐娜今早送我来的  但我需要人送我回家
Donna drove me in this morning, but I'm gonna need a ride home.
这是什么
What's this?
我们的新主板
It's our new motherboard.
我们不是已经有了吗
Buddy, I thought we had one.
这个不一样  我管它叫分层阵列
Not like this. I call it a layered array.
和之前的完全不同
It's really, really different.
-它是...  -没错  我看到了
- What it is is-- - Yeah, I see that.
谁会大量生产一种全新的主板啊
Who's gonna mass-produce a brand-new board from scratch?
你觉得英特尔或AMDYou think Intel or AMD is gonna
均为芯片制造商
会为我们重新调整他们的整个装配线吗
reroute their entire assembly lines for us?
为了卡迪夫电子  可能吗
For Cardiff Electric? Is that reasonable?
我们这是在做什么啊
I mean, what are we doing here?
你说得对  我没想那么远
You're right. I wasn't thinking that far ahead.
-我只是...  -戈登
- I just-- - Gordo,
这是个很棒的点子  但是
it's a killer idea, it is. But
我们只有三个月的时间
we got three months.
我的直觉告诉我
Every bone in my body is telling me
如果我们试着推翻一切重来
that if we try and reinvent the wheel here,
最终只会造出个四不像
man, we're gonna end up with a square wheel.
但是  决定权在你
But, hey, it's your call.
算了  伙计们
Forget it, guys.
-回到最初的设计  -你在开玩笑吗
- Let's go back to alpha. - What? Are you kidding?
我会跟乔说的
I'll tell Joe.
卡迪夫电子  致  卡梅伦·豪伊  382.67美元
你要自己都吃掉吗
You gonna eat all that yourself?
你要抢吗
You gonna try and take it from me?
我是朱迪  这是阿亚科斯和他的混蛋朋友
I'm Judie, this is Ajax and his asshole friend.
-卡梅伦  -卡梅伦有钱吗
- Cameron. - Does Cameron have money?
有机动车吗
Does it have an automobile?
汽车吗  没有
You mean a car? No.
你住这附近吗
You live around here?
-不  我公司大概在一英里外  -公司
- No, I work, like, a mile that way. - Work?
你有工作吗
Like, a job?
我要是出卖自己去工作  还不如死了
The day I sell out and get a job is the day I die.
那都是贪婪物欲的小仓鼠在转轮子
Materialistic greed hamsters spinning their wheels.
你不还想要汽车吗
Oh, says the guy who wants a car.
等天黑我们要去雅皮士街
Come nightfall we're gonna head up to Yuppie Row
在那儿到处留名
and tag the living crap out of it.
在那之前  我们就在这儿待着
Until then we're just gonna hole up here, you know,
随便玩玩  喝点伏特加
thrash a bit, pound some vodka.
但我们没有伏特加了
Thing is, we're short on vodka.
那么就只剩下闲待着了呗
So, you're just gonna hang out here till then?
你有更好的主意吗
Yeah, you got a better idea?
有
Actually, yeah.
卢瑟福女士家的地址
Directions to Ms. Lutherford's.
5点半鸡尾酒会  6点正餐
Cocktails at 5:30, dinner at 6:00.
钱就是钱  对吧
Well, money's money, right?
没事  进去吧
It's okay, you can go on in.
-露露  -约翰
- Loulu. - John.
你气色真好
You look wonderful.
我给你介绍一下  乔·麦克米伦
Let me introduce you here to Joe MacMillan.
-你好  乔瑟夫  -乔·麦克米伦  这是露露
- Of course, Joseph. - Joe MacMillan, Loulu.
崔维斯  这是乔·麦克米伦
Travis, Joe MacMillan here.
乔瑟夫  你是哪人啊
So, Joseph, where do you hail from?
-哈德逊河谷  -我可喜欢那儿了
- Hudson River Valley. - Oh, I adore that area.
-你去过城里吗  -当然  常去
- You get to the city? - Yes, often.
崔维斯和我每年都去  他...
Travis and I go annually. He
不愿去看我资助的歌剧
ignores the opera, I sponsor it.
上一季我们去看了《费加罗的婚礼》
Last season, we saw "Figaro."
结果怎么样
How'd that turn out?
一如既往  约翰
Same way it always does, John.
那是有两百年历史的剧了
It's 200 years old.
但我真不忍看着他们
But I do hate when they try to force
强迫那可怜的孩子娶他母亲
that poor boy to marry his own mother.
没办法  他欠她钱嘛
Of course. He owes her money.
约翰  我看你是带了只鲨鱼来
John, I believe you brought a shark to my table.
没有  就是做生意而已
No, dear. Just a deal.
是啊  内森跟我说了
Yes, yes. Nathan mentioned it.
我自己也去查了一下
I did a little research of my own.
你们的个人电脑项目  我出一千万
I will take 80% of your PC project
占80%的股份
for $10 million.
这有点过分了吧
That's a little aggressive.
约翰  IBM要把你们搅黄了
John, IBM has poisoned your well.
我知道我不是内森·卡迪夫最先想到的人
I know I'm not the first name on Nathan Cardiff's Rolodex,
所以你们现在肯定资金不畅
which means your cash flow is a little stopped up,
就像我第二任丈夫的主动脉
kind of like my second husband's aorta.
我们的预计收入比那要多好几番
Our projected earnings are many multiples of that.
如果你能搞到更好的合同
If there's a better deal for you elsewhere,
你就去吧
you are welcome to take it.
失陪了
Y'all excuse us?
-这简直是疯了  -你小声点
- This is insane. - Keep your voice down.
就这价格  我们不如去银行
At that price, we're better off going to the banks
或是卖给坦迪公司
or selling to Tandy.
好吧  让我跟她谈谈
All right, let me talk her off the ledge.
她对我们的电脑一无所知
This person knows nothing about our machine.
她会给它改头换面然后推出去
She'll wrap it in velvet, call it "Bonnie Blue,"
我们到时根本无力阻止
and we won't be able to stop her.
伙计  我们已经没辙了
Hey, partner, we're already there.
乔瑟夫  一切还好吧
Joseph, is everything all right?
太好了  晚餐上好了
Oh, glorious. Dinner's served.
-他在打电话  -跟马克吗
- He's on the call. - With Mark?
天呐  那我偷偷溜进去递给他吧
Oh, God. Maybe I could just sneak in and hand it to him.
-还是别了  -我可以...
- I wouldn't. - I could just--
马克  这你清楚  我也清楚
Mark, you know that and I know that,
但我们要怎么说服萨默维尔那边
but how can we get Somerville on board?
我已经竭尽全力了
Well, I'm doing everything I can.
你的工作是做什么的
What's your job all about?
软件
Software.
这样啊
Oh, yeah.
我爸爸好像也是做那个的
I think my dad does something like that.
好像吧
I think.
格里梅斯  格里梅斯
Grimace! Grimace!
给服务员小费
Tip the mamacita.
卡梅
Hey, Cam.
他的墨就是为你准备的
This ink's got your name on it.
来  我有个好主意
Here. Got a good idea.
牛奶  味道好极了
喝干啊
Yeah, do it up.
来吧  卡梅  我给你纹上
Come here. Come on, Cam. Let's print it.
相信我  我能行
Now, just trust me. I got it.
他对她说  "绝对不行"
He says to her, "Absolutely not."
她就说"亨利
And she says, "Henry,
我们要把女人送上天环绕地球了
we are flying a woman into orbit on the space shuttle.
我只想要你带我去
All's I'm askin' is for you to take me to--
奥马哈市"
oh, oh, oh, Omaha!"
别闹了  你可真坏
Stop, you're so bad.
乔瑟夫  你怎么看
So, Joseph, what do we think?
奥马哈市吗
About Omaha?
太空计划  萨莉·莱德小姐
About the space program, Miss Sally Ride.
就是骗人的把戏
It's a gimmick.
你不为宇航局打破性别界限感到骄傲吗
You're not proud of NASA for breaking the gender barrier?
苏联人早就做到了  两次
The Soviets did it-- twice.
要么做第一个  要么就不做吗
So it's first or not at all?
作为一个在克隆IBM产品的人  这看法真有趣
Curious outlook for someone who's cloning an IBM.
别对他那么狠啊  露露  他是北方佬
Now, now, go easy on him, Loulu. He's a Yankee.
抱歉
Sorry.
我要跟你们合作
Getting into bed with you boys.
至少得搞清楚你们是什么样的人啊
Least I can do is check the sheets and fluff the pillows.
是不是  崔维斯
Isn't that right, Travis?
我们不会合作的
We're not gonna be partners.
为什么
Why's that?
因为你就是个无聊  恶毒的外行
Because you're a bored, poisonous dilettante
有大把的闲暇时间  却毫无品味
with time on her hands and no taste.
两样东西会毁掉一个公司  卢瑟福女士
Two things destroy companies, Ms. Lutherford--
平庸  和以自我为中心
mediocrity and making it about yourself.
而你这人就是事事以自我为中心
I think you make everything about yourself.
所以你的朋友都是租来的  其他人都讨厌你
That's why you rent your friends and repel everyone else.
博斯  我们还做不做生意了
Boz, we have a deal or not?
我会让巴瑞起草文件
I'll have Barry draw up the papers.
这就对了  乔瑟夫  你看  这并不难
There, you see? Joseph, it's not hard.
要知道自己的地位
It's just knowing your side of the saddle.
还要酒吗
More wine?
崔维斯  给我们拿些白兰地来  我们要庆祝
Travis, bring us some brandy. We're celebrating.
-卡梅  让我做完  -不要
- Yo, Cam, let me finish. - No.
我其实
I don't know
对白兰地毫不了解
jack squat about brandy.
这糖霜太好吃了
Fantastic meringue.
怎么去了这么久
What took you so long?
现在喝白兰地太晚了
It's too late for brandy.
不是白兰地
It's not brandy.
1912年的图克·霍兹沃斯Tuke Holdsworth, 1912.
波尔图葡萄酒的一个品牌
我们喝波尔图时决定的
We decided on a port.
给我来一杯吧
I'll take a snort.
给她倒一杯  崔维斯
Give her a pop, Travis.
那个贱人
That pig-iron bitch
把我们都握在手腕里了
had us right where she wanted us and
然后又把我们踢走
she kicked us to the curb.
我们都说好了的
Hell, we had a deal.
我们不需要她
We don't need her.
你去跟内森说啊
You tell Nathan that.
我们启动项目
We jump-start the project,
把六个月的期限缩短至三个月
crush the timetable from six months down to three.
自己出钱建原型机
Build the prototype on our own dime,
然后拿着我们的筹码去见投资商
then show investors when we have leverage.
你对她说了什么
What'd you say to her?
你做了什么
What'd you do?
我们明天谈吧
We'll talk tomorrow.
这混蛋
And this sumbitch,
我知道他会出红桃A
I know he's gonna cash the heart ace
拿方片飞
and take the diamond finesse.
可他却把明手牌里的黑桃丢出去
Instead, he discards spade from the dummy
拿皇后打
and plays the queen.
我就说"纳威  你是喜欢红人队吗"
I'm like, "Neville, are you a Redskins fan?"
懂吗
You know?
伙计  你还好吗
Hey, man, are you all right?
你真该一起来
I'm telling you, you oughta think about joining 'cause
我真是不想再给这些
I'm getting tired of carrying cards
北方佬和天主教徒拿牌了
for these damn Yanks and mackerel snappers.
老天啊
Aw, man.
你没事吧
Are you all right?
谢天谢地
Oh, thank Christ.
我就跟薇姬说  那些树枝得修剪了啊
I mean, I told Vicky they have got to trim those branches.
人行道被树挡得严严实实
How are you supposed to see cross traffic
叫人怎么看交叉车流啊
when the sidewalk's a damn jungle?
你被解雇了
You're fired.
什么
What?
你被解雇了
You're fired.
地址计算码太长了
The address calculation code. It's too long.
占用太多字节
It takes up too many bytes.
我需要想个办法  抓取地址
What I need is some way of grabbing the addresses
而不用告诉CPU去哪找这个地址
without telling the CPU where to look for them,
就像一个同时是地图的地址簿
like an address book that's also a map.
卡梅伦
Cameron...
你来这儿干什么
why are you here?
我想不出了
I'm stuck.
又干到很晚吗
Another late night, huh?
戈登  你流血了
Gordon, you're bleeding.
听到了吗
You hear that?
它还活着
It's alive.
我给动物管理处打了电话
I called Animal Control.
他们说最仁慈的办法就是直接杀了它
They said the kindest thing is to just kill it.
-或许你可以...  -唐娜
- Maybe you could-- - Look, Donna,
我不会出去的
I'm not going back out there.
-我今天真的很不顺  -好吧
- I've had kind of a day. - Okay--
我会脱下鞋
I'm gonna take off my shoes,
去吻女儿  然后去洗洗
kiss the girls, and wash up,
好吗
all right?
高原五金
人人影视
倾情奉献
翻译
CiciXT
磁芯章鱼X
翻译
木浅薰
冬麟
翻译
某豚
如是我闻
翻译
ddj   七七
草梅伦
时间轴
Kallen 芒果树叶
特效
宝宝
电脑狂人
第一季
第三集
校对&总监
草草
后期
饿得慌
顾问
大伟昔